

Curriculum Vitae for Sebastian Franco Ulloa

Personal information

Address: Helgesens gate 14D E-mail: sebastian.ulloa@xal.no

0553 Oslo Phone: +47 466 79 133

Born: 28.07.1993

Summary

Consultant at Expert Analytics AS. PhD in biotechnological sciences with a background in physics and chemistry. My areas of interest include data science (analysis and visualization), machine learning, drug discovery, nanomaterials, and the theory of evolution. My values are based on the scientific method, critical thinking, and teaching. I am an analytical and compassionate person prompt to hear different perspectives on the same problem, to consolidate them into the most informed and reasonable judgement possible.

Technical skills

Applications Supervised machine learning, Molecular dynamics, Mathematical mo-

deling, Data visualization, Finite element methods, Design of experi-

ments, Scientific writing

Languages Python, C, SQL, bash

Packages Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Pandas, Matplotlib, Bokeh, Tkinter, Se-

aborn, Numpy

Tools Ipython, GitHub, Linux, VMD, Gromacs, Microsoft Office Suite

Education

2017 – 2021 PhD Biotechnological sciences. Italian Institute of Technology. Ge-

noa, Italy. Published six articles (plus three submitted and two in preparation) in peer-reviewed journals on innovative research Thesis title: "Multiscale Modeling of Metal Nanoparticles for Biotechnological ApplicationsDeveloped skills at proposing research questions, designing

experiments, programming, and data analysis

2017 – 2020 Data science certificates of accomplishment. DataCamp, Inc. On-

line. A 245-hour course covering supervised and unsupervised learning with scikit-learn Python's toolkit and SQL database querying Developed skills in data processing, data visualization, linear/logistic models,

SVM, CART, XGBoost, NLP, and deep learning

expertanalytics.no

2020 Leading Digital Transformation online course (6 weeks). Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Professional Education. A 6week online course on the implementation of artificial intelligence, blockchain, cloud computing, the internet of things, and cybersecurity in organizations and companies 2012 - 2017BSc. Physics. University of Los Andes. Bogota, Colombia. Thesis title: Simulations of a Weakly Self-Interacting Fluid Using Lattice Boltzmann Methods.Graded 5.00/5.00 2011 - 2016BSc. Chemistry. University of Los Andes. Bogota, Colombia. Thesis title: "Application of Molecular Mechanics for the Discovery of Novel Microbial IIA Topoisomerases Inhibitors. Graded 5.00/5.00 2016 - 2019Modern Physics at All Scales summer school. University of Leiden. Leiden, The Netherlands. Summer program aimed at bachelor students to learn about multiple research branches and applied physics by leading experts

Professional experience

2021 – Present	Consultant. Expert Analytics. Oslo, Norway. Implement mathematical models and data science solutions to innovate and optimize indu-
	strial processes
2018 - 2021	Research collaborator. Italian Institute of Technology. Genoa, Italy.
	Employed atomistic and coarse-grained molecular simulations to
	study functionalized nanoparticles interacting with biomacromolecules
	Targeted human and bacterial DNA topoisomerases for the develop-
	ment of novel anticancer and antimicrobial compounds Applied stati-
2019	stical methods to analyzehundreds of gigabytes of data Guest researcher (6 months). Hylleraas Centre for Quantum Mo-
2019	lecular Sciences. Oslo, Norway. Collaborated with the research group
	of Prof. Michele Cascella in the study of charged colloids aggregation
	Developed skills in data processing and analysis with Python
2016	Part-time professor (6 months). University of Los Andes. Bogota,
	Colombia. Successfully devised and delivered training in analytical che-
	mistry and laboratory practices for a diverse group of undergraduates.
	Feedback from the students gave me a teaching grade of 3.72/4.00
	Graded over 50 assignments per week including lab reports, workshops, quizzes, and exams
2015 – 2017	Teaching assistant. <i>University of Los Andes. Bogota, Colombia.</i> In-
2010 2011	structed weekly 2-hour lectures to 10-50 students on general, theo-
	retical, computational, and physical chemistry topics Created a safe
	learning environment for students while promoting an ethical class-
	room code-of-conduct
2016	Accompaniment program tutor. University of Los Andes. Bogota,
	Colombia. Tutored five freshmen students in science-related subjects
	(chemistry, physics, mathematics, and biology) monitoring their progress, issues, and concerns related to university life
	gress, issues, and concerns related to university me

Languages

English Highly proficient in speaking and writing

Italian Proficient in speaking and intermediate writing skills

Spanish Native

Personal skills

Data Intrinsically motivated to creating visually appealing representations

visualization of data

Problem Interested in merging seemingly disconnected concepts into innovative

solving and creative perspectives

Statistics Solid background in statistics resulting from a training in scientific

research

Teaching Passionate about sharing knowledge both in formal and informal set-

tings

Some interests and hobbies

Leisure Music, knitting, pet-sitting

Miscellaneous Generative art, the Theory of Evolution, jewel crafting

Physical Boxing, dancing, acrobatics, yoga, hiking

activity